Finding Aid for the Philippine Zines Collection LSC.2281
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Of Fake Monuments, 2013 December 12; Villacorta, Claire (Box 6, Folder 8)
  A zine of poems written over the course of many years. The poems reference everyday life, music, food and drive through the city.
  Poetry; Relationship; Art; Literature
- One Night, I Dreamt Of White Moths., 2017; Sanijon, Trisha; Cubaohaus (Box 6, Folder 9)
  A black and white comic about a dream the narrator has about white moths. The narrator focuses on terminal illness, death and stories of mourning she's experienced.
  Dreams; Mourning; Funerals; Superstition; Culture; Folklore
- Oo Nga Naman, 2012; Nada, Marcushiro; National Gulaman Authority (Box 6, Folder 10)
  This zine is packed with various black and white cartoons, illustrations, and doodles. It includes a short comic on how Pinocchio's little brother came to be, illustrations of bike-riding monsters, and deathly pop-locking.
  Puns; Art; Culture
- Our Lover's Prayer, 2015 (Box 10, Folder 34)
- The Outer Garden: A Few More Blossoms, undated; Villa, Noel; Sangalang, Liana Maris (Box 8, Folder 19)
  Stories and poems that provide a different perspective to Genesis, or how the world as we know it came to be.
  Genesis; Literature; Religion; Science
- Over and Under, 2013; Campos, Rolf (Box 6, Folder 11)
  This zine is a compilation of "bugto" or Tagalog riddles. Each riddle is written in various calligraphy styles and accompanied by doodles.
  Riddles; Bugto; Calligraphy; Art; Culture; Language
- Pagsaulo Ng Mga Panghalip, 2017; Cledera, Shaunnah Ysabel; Magpies Press (Box 6, Folder 12)
  "Memorizing Pronouns," has monochromatic photos paired with the notes from a dream, and are printed on tracing paper that has been handstitched together, then published in Dumaguete City, Negros Oriental, Philippines in 2017.
  Photography; Photo Poetry Zine; Art; Language; Literature
- Palaging Mayroong Dito Nagsisimula, 2016; Samson, Romel; Librong LIRA (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Filipino poems that heavily reference European art and artists in its title. The poems allude to the struggles a person has with dealing with the heavy, restrictive church.
  Poetry; Vienna Secession; European Art; Art; Literature; Religion
- Palaso, 2017 October; Hukom, Marian (Box 6, Folder 14)
  This is a comic about Dark Cupid, who follows Cupid around and pulls their arrow out, causing the loss of love and heartbreak.
  Romance; Hugot; Cupid; Folklore
- Pannacotta, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Paper Monster Press, 2010-2013 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Paper Monster Press is transgenre zine that started in Cavite, Philippines in 2010. There are both Tagalog and English works in this zine, which are separated in the page of contents. Each issue revolves around a different theme and includes illustrations, literature, and music playlists from different authors and artists around the world.
  Horror; Art; Folklore; Literature; Music
  - Asuang Issue, 2010 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - I, Icarus, 2013 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Sandigmaan Issue, 2012 March 2 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - S/TRIP, 2011 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Issue 2, 2010 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Para 'To Sayo, undated; Alfonso, April; Collantes, Ela (Box 6, Folder 16)
  An anthology of different one-shot comics about unrequited love, pining, and heartbreak. These were inspired by Session Road's song, "Gusto Lang Kita Makita."
  Anthology; Hugot; Unrequited Love; Anthropology; Culture
- Paradise is Very Nice, 2017; Electrolychee (Box 6, Folder 17)
  This zine contains 47 worn and simple jeepney vinyl decal art as a tribute to Philippine's 7,107 islands. These vignettes portray scenes and themes from Filipino reality, often using images of mountains, palm trees, beaches, boats, and citylines.
  Mabini (Batangas, Philippines); Folk Art; Realism; Art; Business; Geography; History
- Penzette - ang dyornal ng mga Lagalag, 2009-2011 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  Penzette, based on the dish Pancit, is a journal of and by nomadic writers who tell stories of hardship and poverty.
  Hunger; Call to Action; Pancit Canton; Poverty; Colonization; Culture; Education; Literature; Politics
  - Penzette - ang dyornal ng mga Laglag, 2009; TINTA Writer's Guild (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Instant Penzette Canto*, 2011; Sulat Kamay Writers Guild (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Periphery, 2015 December; Uy, Karize Michella (Box 6, Folder 19)
  A small, 10 page, accordion zine with black and white photos with the subject of the photo lingering at the corners or edges of the frame.
  Folded Books; Photography; Art
- Pia The Teenage Albularyo, undated; Marcelo, Anna (Box 6, Folder 20)
  This zine is about Pia, a young albularyo or witch doctor, who is awakened by a spirit that the agimat necklace around her neck follows.
  Aswang; Anting-anting; Albularyo; Agimat; Culture; Folklore
- Pigs and Beavers Oneshot, undated; Giodesk; Reynaldo, Angelo L.; Garcia, Bugsy; Chain Mason (Box 6, Folder 21)
  This features two one-shot comics. The first is in Isang Tagalog and is about Angelito, a poor boy trying to rise up to the world to write a letter for a chance to meet the girl of his dreams. The second comic is in English, and is about a pig that is oblivious to its situation of getting fattened to be butchered.
  Poverty; Pigs; Culture; Bieber, Justin
- Pinay Feminist Playbook: Notes on Presidential Chauvinism, 2017 May; Santiago, Katrina Stuart (Box 6, Folder 22)
  There notes on presidential chauvinism call out the way President Rodrigo Duterte has perpetuated the culture of machismo and chauvinism in the Philippines. In this zine, Duterte has been quoted, and proven to be a promoter of adultery and disregard to women's dignity. The essays in this zine emphasize the need for women to be treated with respect, and how the current administration disregards laws and common human decency that ensures that.
  Feminism; Machismo; Chauvinism; Culture; Literature; Politics; Duterte, Rodrigo
- The Pinoy Monster Boyfriend Anthology, 2017 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  A Filipino-made collection of stories and art surrounding LGBTQ+ characters and their monster boyfriends from Philippine mythology.
  LGBT; Relationship; Folklore
- Pista ng San Kubler, 2014; Raza, Love Joy L.; The Cabinet (Box 6, Folder 23)
  This zine contains a short story that references Dr. Elisabeth Kübler-Ross' 5 stages of grief and loss. The story takes place in a dentist's office, where the main character inches towards the dawn and acceptance of their own death.
  Grief; Stages of Grief; Culture; Literature
- PLZ., 2017; Gatusby (Box 6, Folder 24)
  A compilation of doodles with words and scribbles that have been piling up in Gatusby's office drawer. Most of them contain puns and references to pop culture.
  Doodles; Pop Culture; Art
- Poblacion, 2017; Dela Rosa, A.; Mari, Reya (Box 6, Folder 25)
  A poblacion is considered the commercial and industrial center in a municipality. This zine contains photographs, prose, and poems about different stories of people leaving and being left behind in these old towns for the city.
  City Life; Culture; Geography; Literature
- Prefixes, 2017; Peroz, Merl; De Los Trinos, Reyzeljan; Arts Diocese of Manila (Box 6, Folder 26)
  A series of short stories that range from a retired activist standing by the lines of louder, younger ones, a first date gone right, a small glimpse of corruption in an Immigration Bureau office, and more.
  Corruption; Rallies; Anthropology; economics; Literature; Politics
- Prescription Pad, 2017 December; Que, Patricia Camille; Espino, Kael; Atienza, Jmar; Kalapati Retrograde (Box 6, Folder 27)
  A chapbook of poetry and fiction published by Kalapati Retrograde in Manila, Philippines. The poems and fictional stories in the chapbook are on pages that are formatted to mimic a prescription pad. Many of the poems and stories allude to Biblical references and death.
  Chapbook; Health; Literature; psychology; Religion
- Probinsyana Problems, 2016 (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Procrastination, 2017; Rosales, Ranzell (Box 6, Folder 28)
  A comic about a boy who procrastinates doing his homework so much that they start to haunt his dreams.
  High School Life; Procrastination; Education
- A Promise is a Promise, 2013; Campos, Rolf (Box 1, Folder 14)
  This zine contains collaged images of Western and Eastern artworks, blueprints, product labels, and various snippets of writing. Under the title, it says "sa hirap at sa ginhawa," which is a Filipino wedding vow translating to "through hardship and through ease."
  Wedding Vows; Art
- Promising Actress, undated; Aguilar, Francis Miguel L. (Box 6, Folder 29)
  A zine that contains a short, 5-chapter story about two office workers, one a promising upcoming actress, and the other the man who has taken a liking to her.
  Office Life; Acting; Film; Literature
- Pseudocuments, 2013; Acuña, Tilde (Box 6, Folder 30)
  Pseudocuments: Volume Two was printed in Diliman, Quezon City. The zine contains both published, but mostly unpublished collection of files, facts, figures, photopgrahs, and images.
  Science fiction; Religion; Literature; Science; Technology
- PSST! YEAH, YOU., undated; Parallon, Archilles (Box 6, Folder 31)
  This zine contains vibrant illustrations by Archilles Parallon. The illustrations have little context, but the red, yellow, and blue color scheme used on the cover implies that the title's classic greeting and call is directed at Filipinos. A few of the illustrations take on themes of Filipino culture and resistance.
  Illustrations; Art; Culture
- The Purest and Saddest Form of Seduction, undated; San Buenaventura, Ma. Rosette Bumanglag (Box 8, Folder 21)
  This zine contains poems and geometric art. It describes art itself as the purest and saddest form of seduction, talks about the allure of having the ability to put color onto a white canvas, of having an artists' touch bring something into life.
  Art Block; Geometric Art; Art; Literature
- Puso'y Dos, 2013 December; UP UGAT (Box 6, Folder 32)
  Puso'y Dos is a title that entails the heart being broken in two. From romantic pining, betrayal, break-ups, loss of a parent, and more-different forms of heartbreak are expressed through the poems and short stories in the zine.
  Heartbreak; Pusoy dos; Literature
- Qu'est-ce Qui Avee Dirty Sanchez? A Serious Guide to Erotic Poetry, 2017 December; Sichauco, Hjorleif (Box 6, Folder 33)
  This zine is a guide by Hjorleif Sichauco, a Norwegian-Filipino writer, on how to write erotic poetry. Hjorleif encourages to find the Sex in other aspects of life outside of the act itself. The zine breaks down how to express certain sentiments or lines so that they are more sensual and convincing. This zine introduces a process for writing about sex conducted that falls under the guidelines of statistical methods in medical mesearch.
  Erotic Poetry; Research; Education; Language; Literature
- Rated XYZ, 2017 August-September; Daga, Dudong; Panelo, Conrad; Sa Kalye, Lapis (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Rated XYZ is a zine that includes poems and short stories that revolve around the theme of oppression, resistance, and corruption in the Philippines. The second issue is a single piece: a long letter, along with song lyrics, for a friend who has passed away. The second issue is a letter written before committing suicide. The zines were published and distrubuted in Cavite, Philippines.
  Davao City (Philippines); Davao City Bombing; War on Drugs; Drugs; Violence; Suicide; Business; Culture; economics; Education; Literature; Music; psychology; Politics
  - Rated XYZ Volume 1 Issue 1, 2017 August (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Rated XYZ Volume 1 Issue 2, 2017 September (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Regla Pregnant with Potential, 2012; Campos, Rolf (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Regla is the slang term for menstruation periods in the Philippines. Some of the depictions include a cartoon depiction of period-havers as a restless wrestler and wolfman in a fight, literally melting into a monster, and having daggers for eyes.
  Menstruation; Periods; Art; Health
- Remainder, undated; Tiu, Pau; Miru (Box 7, Folder 3)
  A zine about the journey of two people learning how to navigate a long-distance relationship. The things mentioned in this zine reflect what must be let go, and what must be kept, in order for the long-distance relationship to survive. This zine is a 2-color risograph zine printed by Bad Student in Manila, Philippines.
  Long-Distance Relationships; Art; Literature
- Ren & Namjoon's Great Aloladventure, undated; Poblete, Cathy (Box 7, Folder 4)
  A Pokemon zine about a heartbroken trainer and their level 5 Rowlet. An underachieving pokemon trainer who decides to go back home with their Pokemon after a few adventures.
  Pokemon; Rowlet; Culture
- Resuscitation, undated; Agustin, Lex; Gonzales, Paulyne; Magpies Press (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Rescusitation is a zine with different watercolor illustrations of lungs, accompanied by poetry. The lungs become central to these poems, as they become the site for metaphors about grief, mental illness, and heartbreak.
  Poetry; Watercolors; Mental Illness; Lungs; Art; Literature
- Roadtrip para po!, undated (Box 10, Folder 45)
- Rue, 2012; Agregado, Mica (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Rue is a zine about a relationship that is slowly falling apart. The title takes on two meanings: Rue as in the evergreen plant, and rue as in regret. The story of the digressing relationship was punctuated with how the different plants in the garden bookmarked their relationship. One saw this garden as the only source of comfort and happiness, and the other was never as mindful or understanding of that fact.
  Plants; Gardening; Art; Literature
- The Rules of Love, 2012 January; Ang, Grace Kelly; Basilio, Patricia; Ligot, Kabel Mishka (Box 8, Folder 22)
  Each poem, created by blacking out the lines around certain words or phrases, is a reference to the rules of love created based on De Amore of Andreas Capellanus. The poems are collaborated by different poets to show a more cynical take on love by writing about how these rules are broken, and how love causes suffering. Printed on the back page is a short definition of love, surrounded with photos of birds and their names to show how fleeting love is.
  Erasure Poetry; Sexuality; Family; Literature
- Sa Kasuluk-Sulukan Ng Kalye Padrelima, 2017; Lasar, Charmaine; Balangay Books (Box 7, Folder 7)
  A story about a man who runs into two childhood friends after returning to his hometown to find himself.
  Barkada; Homecoming; Midlife Crisis; Culture
- Sa Wakas, 2016; Tena, James Luigi T.; Librong LIRA (Box 7, Folder 8)
  This is a collection of Filipino poems about separation, distance, and heartbreak.
- sad diary #1, undated; Marcelo, Anna (Box 7, Folder 9)
  This is a visual diary about a girl who is negatively impacted by polycystic ovary syndrone, physically, emotionally and mentally.
  Mental Health; Eating Disorders; Body image in women; Infertility; Polycystic ovary syndrome; Health; psychology
- SADGIRL, undated; Marcelo, Anna (Box 7, Folder 10)
  A visual autobiographical zine about being a sexual assault survivor and the emotional vulnerabilities that impact her body image, sexual experiences, coping mechanisms and mental health.
  Eating Disorders; Sexuality; Rape; Self-injurious behavior; Health; psychology
- Salad Days, 2012 October; Sy, Albert; Nine Iron (Box 7, Folder 11)
  This is an autobiographical zine published by Manila, Philippine's Albert Sy in October 2012. The zine featuers childhood photos and drawings from his "salad days," 1986-2006, when he was still young and inexperienced with life. The photos start with him as a baby, to being a young schoolboy, and to being a young man who skates and goes to punk shows.
  Photography; Childhood; Doodles; Punk; Anthropology
- Salamin Ni Ma-Las, 2014; Malonzo, Mervin; Haliya Publishing (Box 7, Folder 12)
  After Ma-las the sorcerer died, many attempted to rob the temple where he used to live. This is a story the curse of the sorcerer's mirror, and how it traps anyone who dares to come and take its power in an infinite loop.
  Fantasy; Mirror; Curses; Folklore
- Samplr, 2013; Yumul, Nelz (Box 7, Folder 13)
  These zines provide samples of illustrations, doodles, and graphic designs by Nelz Yumul. Everything in this zine are done digitally and serve to showcase Yumul's different illustration techniques. The samples in these zines includes original ideas, but also borrows some characters such as ones from Star Wars and the Marvel Universe.
  Digital Art; Art
  - Samplr 2 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Samplr 3: We Will Doodle Edition (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Samut Sari 4: House Arrest Edition, 2017; Batocabe, Abbey (Box 7, Folder 14)
  A compilation of sketches of a wide assortment of things that can be found at home.
  Sari-sari; Culture
- Say Your Peace Now: A Hang 'Em High Supplement, 2014 March; Bandoy, Argie; Ching, Mariano; Oliveria, Jayson; Saturnino Basilla (Box 7, Folder 15)
  This serves as an accompanying catalog for Hang 'Em High exhibition that occurred from March 8-29 in 2014.
  Photography; Exhibit; Western; Art; Culture
- Seeing Double, 2016 September; Patch, Polly; Monday Minored (Box 7, Folder 16)
  Seeing Double is a zine printed by Polly Patch, an up and coming clothing brand based in Quezon City. Encased in a matching envelope, this pink and purple pastel zine showcases different illustrations of girls-always double in numbers-in fashionable attires and artsy poses.
  Feminism; Friends; Art; Business; Culture
- Seventh Sense, 2017 May; Macalino, Andrea; Mendoza, Aziel; This Is It Pancit Productions (Box 7, Folder 17)
  Three chapters to a coming-of-age story that centers around the idea of the "seventh sense." The seventh sense is emotions, and these chapters shows how complex and sensitive these things are.
  Markets; Debut; Literature
- Sex Offenders, undated; Celestino, Dustin (Box 7, Folder 18)
  Dustin Celestino's selected works of politically incorrect sexual comedy. Designed as a script, these works are meant to be performed out loud in order to convey the comedy, and create a culture that accepts sex as part of people's lives.
  Sexuality; Performance; Sex Positivity; Comedic Erotica; Anthropology; Literature
- Shiver, 2017; Bernardo, James; Yleana, Geonard; Torres, Vince; Pelikomiks Studios (Box 7, Folder 19)
  A horror anthology ranging from a virus zombie outbreak, to a possessed little girl, and finally, to a mishap in a broken elevator. Each story is accompanied by illustrations that give visuals to horror stories that entail.
  Horror; Religion
- The shortest 12 hours of my life, 2016 (Box 10, Folder 38)
- Show Your Solution, undated; Diklap (Box 7, Folder 20)
  Show Your Solution is comic about a student who has a nightmare about an apple monster attacking him after failing to show their solution for a word problem that involved apples. The "Ibang Kalokohan," which translates to "the other follies" features more illustrations of different monsters.
  School Life; Monsters; Illustrations.; Math
- The Side Effects of Radiation, 2013; UP Writers Club (Box 8, Folder 23)
  This zine utilizes the disjointed feeling of collages and black out poetry in order to show the distress and turmoil caused by radiation. It alludes to the trauma experienced by those whose families and homes were ravaged by nuclear war.
  Poetry; collage; War; Nuclear War; Literature
- Sigue Sigue Philippine Criminal and Gang Tattoo Sampler, 2013 March; Saturnino Basilla (Box 7, Folder 21)
  This zine is a tattoo sampler with illustrations based on the tattoos of criminals and gang members in the Philippines photographed by Sidney Snoeck, a Manila based photographer. The foreword written by Manuel Alvero, talks about the implication of these tattoos, and the difference between its meaning and its significance. The zine includes a free sample of a silkscreened postcard, and was printed in Manila, Philippines.
  Criminals; Tattoos; Gangs; Art; Culture
- Sikami, 2013 November; Pangalatoons (Box 7, Folder 22)
  A comic book anthology that has 10 different stories and illustrations within it. The stories range from very domestic topics like a couple going through pregnancy, to superheroes, to a spy couple.
  Anthology; Superheroes; Relationship; Anthropology
- Silang Napagbilinan, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  A small zine that calls to action to wage a revolution. The title translates to "Those who are charged to." This zine describes different reasons why the people must wage a revolution, which is the solution for the poverty that causes people to die.
  Revolution; Prayer; Health; Literature; Religion; Politics
- Sinigang: Kwento Ng Lumbay, 2015 August; Aquino, Ardie; Ardie Aquino Comics (Box 7, Folder 24)
  A mini-cookbook on how to make sinigang. It includes the necessary ingredients, the instructions, and the memories attached to making food alone, or with a loved one.
  Food; Sinigang; Culture
- Sinkian Bin, volume 2.5, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Sisters, 2017 February; Chuatico, Danielle (Box 7, Folder 25)
  A comic about two girls who find sisterhood in the most unexpected situations. They help one another from the moment they met as one was crying in the bathroom because of her biological sister, the other was trying to get out of a bad date.
  Barkada; Family; Feminism; Sisterhood; Culture
- Small City Lovers, 2013; Recidoro, Zeny May Dy; Mantaring, Jero (Box 7, Folder 26)
  A collection of short stories about lovers, and deeper descriptions and stories about Small City, a dream city. Each page also has a minimalistic illustration that pertains to the words on the page.
  Romance; Literature
- So Far, 2017; Lim, Andrea D. (Box 7, Folder 27)
  A poetry zine that has both English and Filipino poems that carry religious themes to tell stories about absence, displacement, hardship, and love.
  Homesickness; Displacement; Literature; Religion
- Something Happened Today, undated; Cledera, Shaunnah Ysabel; Magpies Press (Box 7, Folder 28)
  This is a zine with poems written in English and Tagalog that brings the idea that every moment that passes by is a moment that brings everyone closer to the inevitable end. It does so in a matter-of-fact way that doesn't paint death in fear, but rather, in a subtle sadness. Each poem is printed on a page that uses a different photo as the background, making some pages vibrant and others dull.
  Death; Mortality; Existentialism; Language; Literature
- Somewhere in the Middle, 2014; De Gala, Ched (Box 7, Folder 29)
  This series has two versions: the kid's version and the adult's version. The covers of the zines show an identical drawing of a pinned location that says "You are there," but as you flip through the pages of each zine, you will immediately notice the difference of the content inside. These two versions have plenty of illustration that match, but it aims to show that there are phrases that will mean something different because it is in a different context of time, while there are some that will remain the same.
  Aging; Growing Up; Art
  - Somewhere in the Middle (Kids Version) (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Somewhere in the Middle (Adult Version) (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Spare Change Paradise Bank, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Spectrum a Stucky Zine, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
- Spilled Milk, 2013 July; Vallejo, Patti; Magpies Press (Box 7, Folder 30)
  Spilled Milk is a zine by Patti Vallejo that that was published in July 2013. It is a zine focused on the objectification of women.
  Depression; Feminism; Gender; Misogyny; Womanhood; Anthropology; Culture
- Split, 2014; Lozendo, Lyra Camille; Refareal, Gerldine; dela Cruz, Tracey (Box 7, Folder 31)
  Split is a zine published in Quezon City, Philippines in 2014. The zine contains three short stories and one poem that deal with topics surrounding complicated relationships that involve adultery, murder, and obsession.